Listen to a short talk on history.
OK.
Since we’ve been talking about mechanics and then we still have a few minutes.
Let me tell you a little about the ancient Greeks
and what they thought about mechanics.
They came up with a system that for them seem to describe
and explain the different motions of different materials.
More than 2000 years ago, Aristotle, the ancient Greek philosopher, assumed that all the
matter on earth were made up of four prime substances, earth, water, air and fire.
Under this system, earth is the densest, water is the next, air is less
dense than water,
and fire is least dense of all.
The heaviest object was made of earth and water,
and lighter object contains significant amounts of fire or air.
So when Aristotle observed that different types of matter had different characteristics.
He assumed this was because the different types of matter were composed of different
amounts of four primary substances.
And Aristotle believes that the motions of objects could also be explained by the
basic natures of four primary substances.
Hum, for example, there was a basic motion of up or down.
Aristotle noticed that when he released most objects, they would drop downwards.
But he also knew that something would rise upwards, like smoke.
Aristotle considered an object downward or upward motion to be the result of dominant
nature of the object.
So according to Aristotle, matter like rock were primarily composed of earth, therefore, they
naturally want to move toward the center of the earth
because this was all thing earthly rested.
But fire had a different resting place, the sky.
So smoke would naturally rise when it was released because it was driving toward
its natural resting place.